<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Known Problems on LEDStrain Wiki</title><link>https://wiki.ledstrain.org/docs/known-problems/</link><description>Recent content in Known Problems on LEDStrain Wiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://wiki.ledstrain.org/docs/known-problems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Problems with human vision</title><link>https://wiki.ledstrain.org/docs/known-problems/list-vision/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ledstrain.org/docs/known-problems/list-vision/</guid><description>Binocular vision # It seems that in many cases bad tech triggers binocular vision problems.
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you ever had any binocular vision problems or if your vision is perfect. Bad tech (or bad lighting) may interact with binocular vision, either causing additional troubles to people who have underlying problems or causing troubles to people who have perfect vision.
A very simple binocular vision self-test is a Brock string test .</description></item><item><title>Problems with monitors/laptops (image/signal/flicker-related)</title><link>https://wiki.ledstrain.org/docs/known-problems/problems_monitors_laptops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ledstrain.org/docs/known-problems/problems_monitors_laptops/</guid><description>PWM # Full-screen flicker of the display backlight. Typically invisible, but easily detectable.
Article about PWM on notebookcheck Iris - software that emulates DC dimming, equalling PWM to that is used for 100% brightness on your device An old and experimental tool to adjust PWM driver frequency on Windows IEEE Std 1789-2015 - recommended practices for PWM in LED lights (pdf) Vcom (LCD screens) # Small flickering of separate pixels, visible with bad factory settings.</description></item><item><title>Problems with monitors/laptops (light/backlight/screen parts-related)</title><link>https://wiki.ledstrain.org/docs/known-problems/list_monitor_laptop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ledstrain.org/docs/known-problems/list_monitor_laptop/</guid><description>1. Undefined problem X # Something in light that affects vergence. Complaints often include piercing white colour, inability to set up a pleasant brightness (screen always feels too bright), and inability to focus on a screen.
Presumably connected to inner screen parts.
Hypothesis here Post where removal of BEF (or similar) layer reduced symptoms with 5 screens Post where a change of polarizer and BEF removal helped partially 2. Excessive blue light # There are some reports that reducing blue light helps, but sometimes not for 100%.</description></item><item><title>Problems with smartphones</title><link>https://wiki.ledstrain.org/docs/known-problems/known_smartphone_problems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ledstrain.org/docs/known-problems/known_smartphone_problems/</guid><description>Poor image quality on a screen # No complaints of eye pain from poor image quality on mobile phones have been reported yet. It is worth mentioning, though. First of all, poor image quality may happen on inexpensive phones or smaller Chinese brands.
May be present on 1-2 screens. If you are concerned about pain on a large number of devices, this is hardly the reason.
The phones of the same model can have different LCD screens (different suppliers, panels, different factories etc.</description></item></channel></rss>